Marco A. Tipitto Cerruti

Phone: (714) 270-6229

Email: marco_tipitto@hotmail.com LinkedIn: bit.ly/marcoTipitto

Personal Site: marcotipitto.github.io

Profile

Front-end focused senior full stack software engineer with 6+ years of professional experience developing and architecting intuitive web and mobile interfaces, versatile services that streamline and simplify complex logistical processes, and implementing quality-focused coding practices and patterns.

Experience

SENIOR MOBILE ENGINEER, EVERI HOLDINGS; LOS ANGELES, CA - 2021 - PRESENT

- Lead project development of a white label casino hospitality framework built with Angular, Ionic & Capacitor that has delivered dozens of iOS and Android 4+ star rated apps with over 50,000 total monthly active users.
- Establish clean architecture and domain driven design practices, coding patterns, and documentation in order to establish a scalable, reliable, and modular micro front end architecture that shortens development time.
- Led development of a casino industry-first self-serve digital loyalty enrollment feature, complete with document scanning and identity verification, that takes the average user less than a minute to complete.
- Architect and execute the delivery of fintech features, including digital wallet and card-less slot and table game play, as well as traffic-driving loyalty features like playable in-app games, drawings and promotions.
- Build custom Capacitor plugins that enable bluetooth, NFC, geolocation and other native features.
- Continuously improve scalability by writing bash automation scripts and yaml pipelines in Azure DevOps.
- Mentor new hires and manage workloads and deadlines for a fully remote team operating across 6 countries. FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, GENERAL MOTORS COMPANY; AUSTIN, TX 2017 2021
- Led the development of rich new Angular and React applications and accelerate the development of additional features by creating reusable components.
- Wrote highly scalable SpringBoot services that empowered GM analysts and dealers to lower operational costs across the North and South American businesses.
- Created fully automated CICD build and release pipelines in Azure DevOps for npm and maven applications
- Increase reliability and reduce incidents in these applications by writing automated end-to-end tests with Cypress, Protractor and Selenium and integrate them into the pipelines.

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, PVCPROPERTIES.COM; AUSTIN, TX, - 2019 - 2020

- Created a new multi-page React application which enables prospective tenants to see available listings and empowers administrators to create, modify or delete these listings.
- Leveraged NodeJS to create RESTful APIs that serviced MongoDB as well as handle OAuth and JWT token authentication.

TEAM LEADER, MICROSOFT SENIOR CAPSTONE PROJECT; TUCSON, AZ, -2016 - 2017

- Led a team that created a fully automated datacenter model in Power BI for Microsoft that delivered location-based datacenter costs and statistics while considering different cooling, power and automation systems.
- Designed new autonomous systems and drew from the latest datacenter technologies to create a system that maximized power savings and minimized both land use and total employee headcount requirements.

Education

University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona – B.S. Mechanical Engineering, 2017, Cum Laude

Skills

- Front End Angular 16, React 17, JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6, HTML, SCSS, CSS, npm, yarn, Capacitor
- Back End NodeJS, MongoDB, Java 8, SpringBoot 2.1, SQL, Firebase, mParticle, Airship
- Pipeline Yaml, Git, Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Cara, Docker, Pivotal Cloud Foundry